Rubaiyat Islam

Practitioner of Strategic Human Resources & Administration





+88 01720021334



rubaiyatislam@yahoo.com



House 41/23, Block-C, Rd-01, Chand Mia Housing Society, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207

Additional Aptitudes

- Business Acumen
- Team Leadership
- Talent Management
- Feasibility Analysis
- Tolerant & People Centric
- Change Management Skills
- Collaboration & Partnering
- Strategic Thinking Competence

Courses & Certifications

- Certified HR Specialist Enrolled from CIPD Asia/2018
- Management & Administration Course/BIAM/Batch-2015
- Business Communication Skills Courses/British Council/2013
- BGMEA Certified/Knitwear/2012

References

- Amit Chakrabortty CMO, Suvastu Properties Ltd. Email: amit_cmo@suvastu.com.bd Cell: +88 01911587887
- Muhammad Ezaz Rasul Sr. Manager, HR & Admin Edison Group Email: ezaz.rasul@edison-bd.com Cell: +88 01711506647



Career Objective

Being a Practitioner of Strategic Human Resources & Administration with above 8 Years of professional expertise exclusively on Human Resource Management & Administration, I'm decently passionate to grab the stunning opportunity with a view to boost up & energize my professional aptitude in any reputable organization through resourceful and result-oriented perception.



Professional Experience

Bashundhara Group

Deputy Manager, HR & Admin (Jan 2020 - Present)

- Accountable to supervise inclusive balance of HR functions HR Strategy, Policy Development & Implementation, Talent Acquisition, Resourcing and Employers Branding, Employee Relation, Engagement & Grievances, Performance Management, Leave & Attendance Management, Payroll & Compensations Management, Organizational Development, Fire, Organizational Health & Safety issues, Legal issues of HR & Admin Dept.
- Organizational design and perform change management initiatives in respond to the need of organizational changes. Leading the change management being the Ambassador of the same to respond to need of organizational changes.
- Build strategic partnership and collaboration with line functions to create ground for acceptance & friendly adoption of HR strategies by business units.
- Execute the line function for people planning and propose new policies, process, procedure to achieve competency & organizational capabilities with periodical review.
- Conduct Strategic headcount planning & effective utilization of manpower by working with functional heads on a cross functional staffing system to energize the entire recruitment process.
- Explore the market best practices in the recruitment and staffing and implement appropriate talent acquisition strategies and hiring plans in the organization.
- Drive the process development in the area of resourcing and policy implementation to ensure compliance in the area of Resourcing.
- Ensure retention of best talent, performance management of overall talent and enhancing the performance driven culture.
- Drive employee engagement in working with executive leadership to develop effective internal communications strategies, processes, tools and training to promote morale and productivity.
- Ensure planning, monitoring, and appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Promote and endorse the issues of safeguarding policy among team members and ensure the implementation of safeguarding standards in every course of action.



Piickme Ltd. (Transportation & Ride-Sharing Company)

Head of HR & Admin (July 2018 - Dec 2019)

- To oversee the compact tasks of HR Strategy Development, Implementation of HR Policies, Talent Acquisition, Resourcing and Employers Branding, Employee Relation, Engagement & Grievances, Performance Management, Payroll & Compensations Management, Organizational Development, Legal issues of HR & Admin Dept.
- Drive recognition on what HR does and how it adds value at the functional, team and distinctive level
- Identify hiring requirements, develops the job descriptions, recruitment plan & conducting the interview program.
- Ensure effective utilization of manpower by working with functional heads on a cross functional staffing system.
- Ensure planning, monitoring & appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Establish and implement efficient systems and procedure to ensure prompt services & effective controls, including data/information and records etc.
- Ensure retention of best talent, performance management of overall talent and enhancing the performance driven culture.
- Ensuring smooth & timely delivery of all arrays of employee services, viz. confirmation, promotion, separation, final settlement, leave & attendance management, HR reports etc.
- To identify promising & poor performing employees, taking corrective action and apprise for action with the coordination of Training & Organization Development Department.



Edison Group (Symphony Mobile & Accessories, Siemens)

Asst. Manager, HR & CS Operation (July 2013 - July 2018)

- Supervise Talent Acquisition for CS & HUB Operations Dept.
- Coordinate Job Analysis, Screening Procedures & Induction Session.
- Fixing up the Key Performance Indicator (KPI) of CS Officers.
- Maintain & Coordinate Employee Performance Evaluation.
- Educate CS Officers to communicate concerning early solution of customer issues.
- Increase product knowledge and customer dealing efficiency to CS Officers.
- Ensure HR & Administrative Support to CS Officers.
- Closely Monitor the Compliance Issues of Customer Service Points.
- Generate advancement scope of Standard Operating Procedure (SOP)
- Ensure Impartial Negotiation with Sales Channel as well as Stakeholders.
- Maintain Smooth relationship with existing vendors as per market strategy.
- Coordinate on Job Training Management to the Customer Service Officer.



Airtel Bangladesh Ltd. (Concern of Hinduja Group)

Sr. Executive, HR Operation (June 2012 - June 2013)

- Provides job candidates by screening, interviewing, and testing applicants; notifying existing staff
 of internal opportunities; maintaining personnel records; obtaining temporary staff from
 agencies.
- Maintenance of human resources records by recording new hires, transfers, terminations, changes in job classifications, merit increases; tracking vacation, sick, and personal time.
- Orients new employees by providing orientation information packets; reviewing company policies; gathering withholding and other payroll information; explaining and obtaining signatures for benefit programs.
- Coordinate on Job Training Management to the Customer Service Officers.



Academic Background

- Prime University, Dhaka Master of Arts in English, CGPA 3.5, April 2015
- National University, Gazipur, Bangladesh Bachelor of Arts in English, 2nd Class, August 2012
- Milestone College, Uttara, Dhaka H. S. C in Business Studies, GPA 3.80, March 2007
- Kakoli High School, Dhanmondi, Dhaka S. S. C in Business Studies, GPA 3.69, Feb 2005



Conferences & Rewards

- Crisis Management, Challenges towards Global Human Resources Joined as the Role of Guest Speaker (Venue: BICC, Organizer: Mind Mapper, Sep 2019)
- Future Trends of HR Management, Presidency University Contributed the Part of Keynote Speaker (Venue: BICC, April 2018)
- Workshop on Modern Concept of HR Management, Dhaka Occupied as the Associate of Stirring Committee (Venue: BRAC Learning Center, June 2017)
- Best Employee of the Year, Edison Group Participated as Award Winner Employee (Venue: Edison Group HQ, Jan 2015)
- Employee of the Quarter, Airtel Bangladesh Ltd.
 Participated as Award Winner Employee (Venue: ASA Tower, Shyamoli, March 2013)